Robert Hillyer Papers
Robert Hillyer Papers
1906-1962
Hillyer, Robert, 1895-1961.
21 linear ft.
Papers of the American author, poet, educator. General, literary, and family correspondence; writings (essays, poems, poetry, reviews, speeches, manuscripts, galley proofs); memorabilia (photographs, clippings, genealogies, daguerreotypes. family Bibles, miniatures, hymnals). Notable correspondents include William Rose Benét, Millicent Todd Bingham, Ben Lucien Burman, Frederick Chamberlin, James Gould Cozzens, Max Eastman, Kimball Flaccus, Horace Gregory, Ralph Hodgson, Robert Huff, Amy Lowell, Archibald MacLeish, Marianne Moore, James B. Munn, Robert Nathan, John Neihardt, Louise Townsend Nicholl, Bliss Perry, Lizette Reese, Lennox Robinson, Paul Rosenfeld, Mark Schorer, Walter Magnes Teller, Mark Van Doren, and Edward Weeks.
149055
Biographical History
Robert Silliman Hillyer (1895-1961) was an American poet. Born in East Orange, New Jersey, on June third 1895, he was educated at Kent School, Harvard College, and the University of Copenhagen. He won the Garrison Prize for poetry at Harvard as an undergraduate and was an editor of the Harvard Monthly and the Harvard Advocate. In World War I he served as an ambulance driver in the French Army at Verdun for which he received a citation, as well as the Verdun Medal, from the French government. After transferring to the American Expeditionary Force in 1918, he rose from private to First Lieutenant and after the war he was attached to the Peace Conference as a courier. Later Hillyer served at the American Embassy in Brussels, Belgium. From 1919 to 1926 he was Instructor in English at Harvard; following that he became Assistant Professor of English at Trinity College, which awarded him an honorary degree on his return to Harvard in 1928. He became Boylston Professor of Rhetoric and Oratory at Harvard in 1937, a chair first held by John Quincy Adams.
Hillyer was Phi Beta Kappa poet six times: at Tufts, 1923; Harvard, 1928; Columbia, 1936; Harvard (for the Tercentenary of 1936);William and Mary (for the Hundredth Anniversary of the founding of Phi Beta Kappa at that college, 1939); and Goucher, 1940. He was president of The New England Poetry Club, 1923 - 1925, twice president of The Poetry Society of America 1949 and 1951 - 1953, a Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences in Boston and a member of The National Institute of Arts and Letters in New York. He received the Pulitzer Prize for Poetry in 1934.
Hillyer retired from Harvard in 1944 after 25 years of teaching. He accepted a Visiting Professorship at Kenyon College in 1948, and, in 1952, accepted a regular professorship at the University of Delaware. In 1954, the H. Fletcher Brown Chair of English Literature was created and Hillyer became the first incumbent.
An amateur composer and a student of music, Hillyer believed that poetry and music are inseparable. Many of his poems were set to music by various composers, such as Herman Luri, Daniel Pinkham, Gordon Sherwood, Ned Rorem, Mervin Whitcomb, Oscar Harveland, Joseph Clokey and John Drake.
Select Bibliography
Selected Bibliography
Following is a list of selected works by Hillyer.
Eight Harvard Poets. New York: Lawrence Gomme, 1917. Poems by Harvard undergraduates, including Hillyer, E. E. Cummings, S. Foster Damon and John Dos Passos.
Sonnets and Other Lyrics. Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1917.
The Five Books of Youth. New York: Brentano's, 1920.
Alchemy: A Symphonic Poem. New York: Brentano's, 1921.
A Book of Danish Verse. New York: The American-Scandinavian Foundation, 1922. Translations from Danish lyric poetry from Oehlenschlager to Johannes V. Jensen (in collaboration with S. Foster Damon and Oluf Friis).
The Hills Give Promise. Boston: B. J. Brimmer, 1922.
The Coming Forth by Day. Boston: B. J. Brimmer, 1923. Metrical arrangements from the Egyptian Book of the Dead together with an essay on the ancient
Egyptian Religion, first published in The Freeman and subsequently reprinted (without the essay) in Van Doren's Anthology of World Poetry.
The Halt in the Garden. London: Elkin Mathews, 1924. Foreword by Arthur Machen.
The Engagement Ring. The Masquerade. Hartford: The Haylofters, 1929.
Prose Masterpieces. New York: Harcourt Brace, 1931 (in collaboration with K. B. Murdock and Odell Shepard).
The Gates of the Compass. New York: The Viking Press, 1931.
Riverhead. New York: Knopf, 1932.
Collected Verse. New York: Knopf, 1933 (awarded the Pulitzer Prize).
Some Roots of English Poetry. Norton, Massachusetts: Wheaton College Press, 1933.
A Letter to Robert Frost and Others. New York: Knopf, 1937.
First Principles of Verse. Boston: The Writer, 1938.
In Time of Mistrust. Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1939.
Pattern of a Day. New York: Knopf, 1940.
My Heart for Hostage. New York: Random House, 1942.
Poems for Music: 1917-1947. New York: Knopf, 1947.
The Death of Captain Nemo. New York: Knopf, 1949.
The Suburb By the Sea. New York: Knopf, 1952.
The Relic and Other Poems. New York: Knopf, 1957.
Robert Burns, Bicentennial Address at Library of Congress. Washington: Library of Congress, 1959.
In Pursuit of Poetry. New York: McGraw-Hill, 1960.
Collected Poems. New York: Knopf, 1961.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Robert S. Hillyer Papers consist of correspondence, manuscripts, and a few items of memorabilia.
The collection of incoming Literary correspondence includes cards, letters, telegrams, notes and other items from poets, authors, playwrights, publishers, and other literary figures, including James Agee, Conrad Aiken, Stephen Vincent Benét, Ray Bradbury, Van Wyck Brooks, John Cheever, Padraic Colum, e.e. cummings, John Dos Passos, Gene Fowler, Robert Frost, Horace Gregory, Aldous Huxley, Helen Keller, Amy Lowell, Arthur Machen, Archibald Macleish, Marianne Moore, Howard Nemerov, Theodore Roethke, Harry Roskolenko, Carl Sandburg, George Santayana, May Sarton, Siegfried Sassoon, Booth Tarkington, Louis Untermeyer, and Marya Zaturenska. Many are letters of appreciation and praise for Mr. Hillyer's works and endeavors, as exemplified by the following quotation from a letter written by Ray Bradbury, on September 10, 1959:
"Quite simply, for a long long time now, you've made me happy, sad, and tremendously alert with your poems. For all this, I want to thank you."
Family correspondence includes incoming correspondence from Hillyer's mother, Mrs. James Rankin Hillyer, siblings Stanley, Lillian and Ethel, and son Stanley H. Hillyer, as well as various other relatives.
Outgoing correspondence consists of 18 folders of assorted letters, cards, telegrams, and other communications from Hillyer to friends, family, and others. Recipients include, among others, John Dos Passos, Ray Bradbury, Louis Kent, and Hillyer's mother.
Four folders of General correspondence primarily consist of fan mail, with a few unidentified items.
Manuscripts consists of handwritten drafts, typescripts, galleys, notebooks, and xerox copies of articles, music, poems, prose, speeches, readings, lecture notes, reviews, and other material written by Hillyer. Many bear Hillyer's handwritten corrections and annotations.
Miscellaneous material contains genealogical material, clippings (both pieces by Hillyer as well as reviews of his work), guest books, photographs, programs for various events, and assorted writings by others.
Memorabilia includes degrees, bibles, photographs, and other assorted items.
Arrangement of the Collection
Literary and family correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. The remaining series are organized in no particular order.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Literature -- American Poetry; Aiken, Conrad, 1889-1973.; Benét, William Rose, 1886-1950.; Bingham, Millicent Todd, 1880-1968.; Briggs, Le Baron Russell, 1855-1934.; Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963.; Burman, Ben Lucien, 1895-1984; Bynner, Witter, 1881-1968.; Copeland, Charles Townsend, 1860-1952.; Chamberlin, Frederick, 1870-1943.; Cozzens, James Gould, 1903-1978.; Damon, S. Foster (Samuel Foster), 1893-1971.; Decker, Clarence Raymond, 1904-1969.; Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970.; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969.; Flaccus, Kimball, 1911-1972.; Fletcher, John Gould, 1886-1950.; Fowler, Gene, 1890-1960.; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963.; Gogarty, Oliver St. John, 1878-1957.; Gregory, Horace, 1898-1982.; Hillyer, Robert, 1895-1961.; Hodgson, Ralph, 1871-1962.; Huff, Robert, 1924-; Huxley, Aldous, 1894-1963.; Johnson, Thomas Herbert.; Kent, Louis.; Lowell, Amy, 1874-1925.; Machen, Arthur, 1863-1947.; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982.; Mason, Daniel Gregory, 1873-1953.; Maxwell, William, 1908-2000.; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972.; Munn, James Buell.; Nathan, Robert Louis.; Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973.; Nemerov, Howard.; Nicholl, Louise Townsend.; Perry, Bliss, 1860-1954.; Reese, Lizette Woodworth, 1856-1935.; Robinson, Lennox, 1886-1958.; Rosenfeld, Paul, 1890-1946.; Schorer, Mark, 1908-1977.; Scott, Winfield Townley, 1910-1968.; Speyer, Leonora, 1872-1956.; Teller, Walter Magnes.; Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-1977.; Van Doren, Mark, 1894-1972.; Viereck, Peter, 1916-2006.; Weeks, Edward, 1898-1989.; Zaturenska, Marya, 1902-1982.; American literature -- 20th century.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Authors, American -- 20th century.; Criticism -- 20th century.; Critics -- United States.; Poets, American -- 20th century.; Book reviews.; Clippings (information artifacts); Drafts (documents); Essays.; Genealogies (histories); Lectures.; Manuscripts for publication.; Musical scores.; Photographs.; Poems.; Songs (document genre); Authors.; Critics.; Educators.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Permission to read family correspondence (Box 6) must be granted by Laura V. (Mrs. Stanley H.) Hillyer; upon her death, permission must be granted by either of her two daughters, Elizabeth V. Hillyer or Francesca P. Hillyer. Mrs. Hillyer is also to be contacted when anyone is interested in the scholarly use of Robert Hillyer's works and papers.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. Robert S. Hillyer, 1963
Lopatnikoff letters and manuscript of completed poems, 1943, unspecified gift.
Inventory
- Literary correspondence
  - Adams, J. Donald, 1959; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    4 Sept. 1959 - TLS Mentions difficulties with collaborator on unidentified work in progress.
  - Agee, James, 1930; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    7 Jul. 1930 - TLS Refers to recent book published by Yale University Press.
  - Aiken, Conrad, 1929-1932; 1935,; 1938-1942,; 1944-1945; 23 Letters, 1 Christmas Card, 1 Card (Box 1)
    Undated - TLS
    [1929] - TLS Mentions work on Emily Dickinson material.
    17 Jul. 1929 - TLS Touches on current literary activity.
    20 Aug. 1929 - TLS
    [1930] - TLS
    13 Nov. 1930 - TLS Comments on poems and format of Hillyer's The Gates of the Compass.
    Dec. 1930 - Printed Christmas Card. Original poem "A.D. 1930" signed by author.
    25 Feb. 1931 - TLS Deals with Aiken's current literary activity with comments on The Coming Forth By Day of Osiris Jones.
    19 May 1931 - TLS Discusses the Pulitzer Prize award for that year and comments on contemporary authors.
    19 Jan. 1932 - TLS Comments on Faulkner, Sophocles, Rilke and Aiken's current financial situation.
    30 Jul. 1932 - TLS Philosophizes on writing with a criticism of Melody of Chaos; comments on Pulitzer Prize for that year and on Edna St. Vincent Millay.
    20 Sept. 1935 - TLS Concerns Robin Flower, poet and translator.
    2 Feb. 1938 - TLS Mentions summer school with comments on recent trip to Mexico.
    6 Feb. 1939 - TLS Relates success of summer school.
    21 Nov. 1939 - TLS Agrees to give reading if his teeth are in satisfactory condition on scheduled date.
    9 Mar. 1940 - TLS Describes loss of teeth and projects for summer school.
    13 Feb. 1941 - TLS Discusses critical reception of author's new book with Cowley on one side and Jarrell leading opposition.
    17 Feb. 1941 - Signed Card. Notes a critical attack by Jarrell on author's new book with comments on Jarrell as a critic.
    4 Nov. 1941 - TLS
    5 Feb. 1942 - TLS Short note delivering annual "Cri de Coeur."
    28 Jul. 1944 - TLS Speaks about anthologies.
    28 Mar. 1945 - TLS Again discusses anthologies and their sales. Holograph notes on side.
    15 May 1945 - TLS Discusses "The Soldier."
  - The Atlantic Monthly, 1956; 1958; 1 Letter, 1 Telegram (Box 1)
    20 Aug. 1956 - TLS Encloses assignment of copyright agreement for Hillyer's article In My Library, Late Afternoon.
    28 Aug. 1958 - Telegram. Accepts Hillyer's One Kind of Colloquy for publication.
  - Ames, Evelyn, 1961; 1 Condolence Card) (Box 1)
    Dec. 1961 - Condolence Card.
  - Armour, Richard, 1949; 1960; 2 Cards (Box 1)
    19 Jun. 1949 - Signed Card. Appreciation of Hillyer's article on The Bollingen Award.
    29 Nov. 1960 - Signed Card. Appreciation of Hillyer's In Pursuit of Poetry.
  - Bacon, Leonard, 1938; 1941; 3 letters (Box 1)
    12 Oct. 1938 - TLS Discusses possibility of Robert Frost leaving Amherst and going to Harvard.
    19 May 1941 - ALS Mentions a gift of $50.00 for Grant Code.
    15 Jun. 1941 - TLS Further reference to Grant Code.
  - Bate, W. J., 1960; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    9 Jun. 1960 - TLS Former student praises Hillyer's ability to teach students to read aloud.
  - Behn, Harry, 1960; 1 letter (Box 1)
    15 Feb. 1960 - TLS Describes current progress on a book of poetry.
  - Benet, Stephen Vincent, undated; 2 Letters (Box 1)
    Undated – ALS
  - Benet, William Rose, 1940; 1945,; 1947-1950; 9 Letters, 1 Card (Box 1)
    19 Dec. 1940 - ALS Long interesting discussion of Benet's Prayer for England with views on the political situation in Europe.
    25 Jul. 1945 - ALS Deals at length with Ezra Pound.
    25 Aug. 1947 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for a Times review of one of the author's works.
    16 Sept. 1947 - ALS Further comments on the review.
    24 Mar. 1948 - TLS Deals with critical attack on Hillyer.
    20 Apr. 1948 - TLS Deals with current works and with young Italian poet Colamussi.
    28 Apr. 1948 - TLS Refers to Colamussi.
    10 May 1948 - ALS Discusses title of a new Hillyer sonnet submitted to the Saturday Review of Literature.
    24 Oct. 1949 - ALS Brief letter enclosing a photo of Benet.
    19 Jun. 1950 - Condolence Card with note from Benet's secretary thanking Hillyer for his sympathy on behalf of Mrs. Benet.
  - Bingham, Millicent Todd, 1945; 1947,; 1949,; 1955; 8 Letters (Box 1)
    10 May 1945 - ALS Praises Hillyer's analysis of Emily Dickinson's reclusiveness in his article in The Freeman of 18 October 1922.
    31 Jan. 1947 - ALS Discusses at length work editing partially published poems of Emily Dickinson.
    26 Jun. 1949 - ALS Praises Hillyer's attack on Bollingen Award and comments on Emily Dickinson project.
    4 Jan. 1955 - ALS
    4 Feb. 1955 - TLS Discusses difficulties in editing of work on Emily Dickinson and notes possibility of Hillyer reviewing same.
    24 May 1955 - ALS Mentions disappointment at finding no review by Hillyer in New York Times and expresses desire to see one by him.
    28 Sept. 1955 - ALS Regrets missing opportunity to visit Hillyer and seeks his criticism of Emily Dickinson's Home.
    5 Oct. 1955 - TLS Mentions unidentifiable Emily Dickinson book.
  - Black, John, 1952; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    15 Jun. 1952 - TLS Praises Hillyer's "Hammock In The Orchard" and comments on modern poetry in general.
  - Bonner, Amy, 1949; 2 Letters (Box 1)
    8 Jun. 1949 - TLS Praises Hillyer's article "Treason's Strange Fruit" and comments on U.S. State Department attitude toward Pound.
    13 Jun. 1949 - TLS Further comments on aforementioned article with copy of a letter written by author to Saturday Review of Literature in reference thereto.
  - Boyle, James Le Baron, 1954; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    19 Nov. 1954 - ALS
  - Boyle, Kay, 1959; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    4 May 1959 - ALS States Boyle's willingness to second nomination of Howard Nemerov to National Institute of Arts and Letters.
  - Bradbury, Ray, 1959-1961; 4 Letters (Box 1)
    10 Sept. 1959 - TLS Appreciation of Hillyer's The Relic and Other Poems containing information that Bradbury's story" The Shoreline At Sunset" was inspired by early Hillyer poem.
    9 Jan. 1960 - TLS Contains anecdote about John Decker and John Barrymore, with enclosed story.
    9 Apr. 1961 - TLS Discusses author's views on writers and critics.
    17 May 1961 - TLS Appreciation of In Pursuit of Poetry.
  - Bradford, Gamaliel, 1922-1923; 3 Letters (Box 1)
    7 Nov. 1922 - TLS Invitation
    16 Nov. 1922 - TLS Discusses Emily Dickinson.
    20 Feb. 1923 - TLS
  - Bridges, Robert, 1920; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    10 Nov. 1920 - ALS Discusses current political situation in England; comments on Hitler and Germany; refers to attacks on Bridges.
  - Briggs, Le Baron Russell, 1916-1917; 1919-1931,; 1933; 39 Letters, 2 Cards (Box 1)
    10 Apr. 1916 - TLS
    26 Jun. 1917 - TLS To Hillyer's mother concerning the publication of Hillyer's first book of poetry.
    30 Jul. 1917 - ALS Discusses Hillyer's book, describes commencement, touches on Hillyer in World War I.
    21 Oct. 1919 - ALS
    25 Oct. 1920 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's book Alchemy and describes a Harvard football game with Centre College, Kentucky.
    22 Nov. 1920 - TLS Discusses Alchemy and One Man's Initiation by John Dos Passos.
    30 Dec. 1920 - TLS Mentions comrades of Hillyer's.
    3 Mar. 1921 - TLS Discusses translation of Danish lyric poets by Hillyer and S. Foster Damon.
    17 Feb. 1922 - ALS Discusses Hillyer's Carmus.
    23 Feb. 1922 - TLS Further remarks about Carmus and comments on publishers.
    18 Jan. 1923 - ALS Discusses translations being made by
    22 Mar. 1923 - TLS Hillyer and Damon. Comments on Carmus.
    26 Mar. 1923 - ALS
    3 Apr. 1923 - TLS
    27 Apr. 1923 - TLS Additional comments on Carmus and Alchemy.
    11 Jun. 1924 - TLS
    26 Dec. 1924 - ALS Request Hillyer to aid in plans for Radcliffe Poetry Club.
    16 Feb. 1925 - TLS
    26 Sept. 1925 - ALS Candidly discusses Hillyer's The Halt In The Garden.
    19 Nov. 1926 - ALS Discusses the author's retirement activities.
    3 Feb. 1927 - ALS Discusses materials for possible use in English 5 at Harvard.
    16 May 1927 - ALS
    24 May 1927 - ALS
    5 Oct. 1927 - ALS
    4 Jan. 1928 - ALS
    1 Apr. 1928 - ALS Praises Hillyer's The Seventh Hill and notes favorite poems in it.
    8 Aug. 1928 - ALS Recommends a student to Hillyer.
    25 Aug. 1928 - ALS Discusses student further, and comments on Briggs' essay recently sent to Hillyer.
    25 Oct. 1928 - ALS Mentions Hillyer's work in English 5.
    4 Apr. 1929 - Signed Card AS Proposes two subjects for next meeting with Hillyer.
    15 Apr. 1929 - Signed Card.
    20 May 1929 - ALS Analyzes and praises unnamed Hillyer platform poem.
    29 May 1929 - ALS Discusses unnamed poem and comments on Briggs' former analysis.
    1 Jun. 1929 - ALS Comments further on Hillyer's poem and Briggs' analysis of it.
    22 Jun. 1929 - ALS
    12 Jul. 1929 - ALS Invites Hillyer and family to Briggs' home.
    8 Jul. 1930 - ALS Recommends individual for assistantship in English 5.
    24 Oct. 1930 - ALS Briefly praises Hillyer's new unnamed book.
    26 Feb. 1931 - ALS
    15 Jul. 1933 - ALS Highly recommends E. G. Barton for teaching position under Hillyer.
  - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1923-1924; 1933,; 1947; 16 Letters (Box 1)
    16 Apr. 1923 – ALS Invites Hillyer to act as on occasional book reviewer for The Freeman.
    30 Apr. 1923 - ALS Discusses possible reviews for The Freeman and commends Hewlett's Extemporary Essays.
    8 May 1923 - ALS Mentions possible review of book on life and times of Tut-Ankh-Amen.
    10 May 1923 - ALS Mentions Hillyer's interest in magic.
    28 May 1923 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for a review.
    19 Jul. 1923 - ALS Requests review of Egyptian History and Art by Quibell and of two new works by Wallis Budge.
    30 Jul. 1923 - ALS Comments on Hillyer's reviews and on an essay by Epicurus.
    13 Aug. 1923 - ALS Discusses possible books to be reviewed by Hillyer for The Freeman among them The Gate of Remembrance and Herman Ranke's Aeqyptian.
    19 Sept. 1923 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for revised version of review of The Gates of Remembrance and requests copy of mislaid essay.
    23 Sept. 1923 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for his essay "The Heart of The Matter" and mentions lost essay "Interpreting The Past."
    6 Oct. 1923 - ALS Comments on two books — Shelley: The Man and The Poet and Father Taft.
    23 Oct. 1923 - ALS Requests Hillyer's article on Chamberlin's "Queen Elizabeth."
    28 Jan. 1924 - ALS States reasons for which The Freeman is to cease publication.
    31 Aug. 1933 - ALS
    9 Sept. 1933 - ALS Discusses collection of letters of Gamaliel Bradford, the inclusion of a Hillyer letter in the same, and the editing of the Charles Newcomb Journal, for which Hillyer recommended Odell Shepard.
    7 Nov. 1947 - TLS Invitational letter of Academy of Arts and Letters.
  - Brown, Abbie Farwell, 1924; 1 Note (Box 1)
    10 Mar. 1924 - Signed Note, with holograph copy of author's poem "Saints and Friendly Beasts" inscribed to Hillyer.
  - Brown, Hunly, 1949; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    3 Jul. 1949 - ALS Detailed appreciation of Hillyer's "Dissection of Pound, Eliot and Company," with mention of a letter in which Eliot supposedly reversed his opinions on Milton.
  - Buchanan, Helen W., 1949; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    14 Jul. 1949 - TLS Student requests help on thesis concerning Hillyer.
  - Budge, E. A. Wallis, 1922-1923; 2 Letters (Box 1)
    28 Nov. 1922 - ALS Grants permission to Hillyer to turn into verse ( The Coming Forth Day) any chapters of author's translation of The Book of The Dead.
    28 Mar. 1923 - ALS Congratulates Hillyer on excellence of The Coming Forth BY Day.
  - Burman, Ben Lucien, 1952; 1956,; 1959-1961; 8 Letters (Box 1)
    20 May 1952 - ALS Describes Burman's book High Water At Catfish Bend.
    24 Jun. 1952 - ALS Repeats requests of previous letter and extends invitation.
    30 May 1956 - ALS Remarks about Seven Stars for Catfish Bend.
    13 Jul. 1959 - ALS Discusses Burman's The Street of The Laughing Camel and possibility of Hillyer's reviewing book for the New York Times Review.
    20 Aug. 1959 - ALS
    19 Sept. 1959 - TLS Thanks Hillyer for review of author's The Street of The Laughing Camel.
    15 Nov. 1960 - ALS Discusses Hillyer's introduction to the author's The Owl Hoots Twice at Catfish Bend.
    15 Jan. 1961 - ALS
  - Butterfield, L. H., 1949; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    30 Jun. 1949 - TLS Praises Hillyer's articles on Ezra Pound and Bollingen Award.
  - Bynner, Witter, 1939; 1942,; 1946-1949,; 1952-1961; 31 Letters (Box 1)
    29 Aug. 1939 - TLS
    21 Sept. 1942 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's First Principles of Verse.
    19 Jun. 1946 - TLS Discusses Bynner's work on Lao-Tzu, his discovery and promulgation of Kahlil Gibran, and comments at length on Gene Fowler.
    16 Oct. 1946 - TLS Remarks on Bynner's feud with Amy Lowell and encloses photographs.
    31 Jul. 1947 - TLS Mentions the author's Take Away The Darkness.
    19 Aug. 1947 - TLS Discusses some of Hillyer's poems, notably "Julia's Room."
    16 Jan. 1948 - TLS with holograph addenda. Refers to Hillyer's Poems For Music.
    23 Jul. 1949 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's stand on Pound controversy with acid comments on William Carlos Williams and other modern poets; contains quote of Aldous Huxley.
    23 Aug. 1949 - TLS Mentions correspondence with W. R. Benet on Pound with clippings enclosed.
    19 Nov. 1952 - TLS Mentions "Carl's" outbreak at Poetry Society of America meeting and author's choice for "Academy nomination"--David Morton.